<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project-team MathHydroNum on DassHydro</title>
    <link>https://mathhydronum.insa-toulouse.fr/the_team/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project-team MathHydroNum on DassHydro</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 15:20:34 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mathhydronum.insa-toulouse.fr/the_team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Objectives</title>
      <link>https://mathhydronum.insa-toulouse.fr/the_team/team_objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 15:24:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mathhydronum.insa-toulouse.fr/the_team/team_objectives/</guid>
      <description>MathHydroNum denotes a French multidisciplinary research project-team offering expertise in numerical hydrology and the software platform DassHydro (Data Assimilation in Hydrology) dedicated to numerical modeling of surface hydrodynamics and hydrology.
The team brings together expertise in computational sciences, hydrology, hydraulics, mathematical models and methods, inverse problems, statistical inference, sensitivity analysis, data assimilation, reduced models, and physically informed neural networks.
The objectives of MathHydroNum are to design models, numerical methods, algorithms, and computational softwares that address scientific challenges in the following areas:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>https://mathhydronum.insa-toulouse.fr/the_team/team_members/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 15:24:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mathhydronum.insa-toulouse.fr/the_team/team_members/</guid>
      <description>Founding teams INSA Toulouse - IMT INRAE Aix (UMR RECOVER) Jérôme Monnier (Professor, founder, co-lead) Webpage Pierre-André Garambois (Researcher, co-founder, co-lead) Webpage Robin Bouclier (Associated member, associate Professor HDR) Webpage Benjamin Renard (Researcher) Olivier Roustant (Associated member, Professor) Webpage François Colleoni (R&amp;amp;D Engineer) Mustapha Allabou (Ph.D. Student 2021-24) Truyen Huynh (Ph.D. student 2022-25) Hugo Boulenc (Ph.D. Student 2022-25) CS Group Toulouse HydroSciences Montpellier Kévin Larnier (R&amp;amp;D Engineer) Webpage Léo Pujol (postdoctoral researcher) Webpage Collaborators Engees-Icube SERTIT-Icube Guilhem Dellinger (Associate professor) Webpage Alessandro Caretto (R&amp;amp;D engineer) IMFT - INPT International collaborators Helene Roux (Professor) Webpage Shangzhi Chen (Assistant Professor, Anhui University of Science and Technology in China) Webpage Partners and co-funders </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
